

Hello,

I'm a software engineer who specialises in UI design and UX.

I have over 10 years of industry experience designing and building web applications.

I'm passionate about finding elegant solutions, and adding some flare and magic, to complex problems.

Industry Experience

SENIOR USER INTERFACE ENGINEER @ CARISTO DIAGNOSTICS

April 2021 → Present

Caristo makes technology which uncovers the hidden early signs of cardiac disease in medical imaging, through advanced analysis and machine learning. The product is a web platform which hosts a plethora of tools aimed at professional analysts and clinicians. I work with the product owner to develop prototypes, and with the development team to engineer these designs into a fully functional user interface. I am responsible for the long-term development and maintenance of the user interface, ensuring it aligns with business goals while meeting stringent medical safety requirements. This involves researching and selecting the right technologies, establishing a clear implementation strategy, supporting test frameworks to ensure quality and compliance, and collaborating with users and product teams to enhance usability. This approach has resulted in the development of a highly robust, efficient and scalable UI-component framework that ensures design consistency across our platform.

Tech: React, Docker, Sketch, MobX, Typescript

USER INTERFACE ENGINEER @ EXONAR

September 2019 → April 2021

Exonar is a data insight platform that connects to a wide range of common sources to crawl, index and visualise a client company's entire data estate. The primary UI focus was on transforming vast, sprawling datasets from a multitude sources into accessible and actionable reports. I played a key role in designing and developing various charting and querying tools, as well as shaping the overall flow and design of the platform, ensuring the product's UX remained at the forefront of the tech industry.

Tech: React, Redux, Sketch, Storybook, Jest, D3, Chart.js

FRONTEND DEVELOPER @ DISCOVER IT

January 2019 \rightarrow September 2019

Discover IT is a web agency, catering to medium-sized businesses. They design and build websites and support commercial web services across a number of industries. In this role, I managed a diverse range of projects within tight timeframes, working across the entire lifecycle - from wireframe design to development, deployment and maintenance. Operating in a fast-paced environment with multiple concurrent projects required adaptability and efficient learning. Success was defined by delivering responsive, reliable, and visually stunning digital experiences to "wow" customers under tight deadlines.

Tech: Vue, React, Sketch, Adobe, CSS, SASS

SOFTWARE ENGINEER @ CGI

September 2012 → December 2018

CGI is a large scale business and IT consultancy. I joined CGI after completing A-levels at school, and during my first three years there, my time was split between work and the sponsored degree program. CGI provided exposure to a wide variety of enterprise clients early on in my career, and allowed me to experience a variety of different roles in a large corporate environment. I completed projects for the UK Environment Agency, The Galileo satellite network, the UK Smart Meter program, Shell, the Ministry of Defence and more. During this time I developed a skillset targeted towards modern web development and UX design.

Tech: Javascript, D3

Qualifications

BUSINESS MANAGEMENT @ UNIVERSITY OF WINCHESTER

Bachelor's Degree | First Class Honours | 2012 → 2015

Undertook in collaboration with the CGI sponsored degree program. This saw me studying part-time alongside full-time employment at CGI.

Website

Tech demos, hobby projects, and other perpetual works in progress: www.dominicbutler.work

Technical Skillset

Storybook Graphic Design Sketch MobX FS₆ Docker css modules React Prototyping Webpack Typescript UI Design Component Design System Vite Jest D3 UX Design Data Visualisation Vue Unit test Node Animation Git Rollup Agile Redux React-router Three.js NPM